A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Homes, Series I FA318
Rockefeller Archive Center
- 10 West 54th Street, NYC
  - 10 West 54th Street - Duveen Brothers - Porcelains, 1902-1919 (Box 134, Folder 1333)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. purchases, refusals. Lengthy bargaining over porcelains. Duveen stating his position on the value of art objects and on the way in which he conducts his business affairs. Large purchases almost every year from 1914-1932.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Duveen Brothers - Porcelains, 1919-1930 (Box 134, Folder 1334)
  - 10 West 54th Street - Duveen Brothers - Porcelains, 1930-1936 (Box 134, Folder 1335)
  - 10 West 54th Street - Duveen Brothers - Porcelains - Ming Bottles, 1924-1928 (Box 134, Folder 1336)
    Purchase of three pieces, long bargaining.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Duveen Brothers - Porcelains - Repairing Porcelains, 1915-1919 (Box 134, Folder 1337)
    Duveen repairing John D. Rockefeller, Jr. porcelains, making stands, porcelain covers. Duveen commissions a Japanese repairman.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Duveen Brothers - Porcelains - E. Takenaka - Repairs, 1923-1938 (Box 134, Folder 1338)
    Repair of Chinese porcelains.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Duveen Brothers - Morgan Collection, 1915-1916 (Box 134, Folder 1339)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. purchased Morgan Collection of Chinese porcelains in 1915 for approximately $1,500,000.00 (in stock). Gift of Pennsylvania stock from John D. Rockefeller to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. for the Collection. Lengthy discussion over price, quality, condition (etc.) of porcelains in Collection. Subsequent exchange of some of the pieces in the Morgan Collection.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Duveen Brothers - Morgan Collection - Option on Pennsylvania Stock, 1915-1916 (Box 134, Folder 1340)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. exercises option and pays Duveen for Pennsylvania stock they are holding.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Fukushima, 1923-1942 (Box 135, Folder 1341)
    Dealer in porcelains. Scattered purchases.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Duveen Brothers - Tapestries, 1922-1936 (Box 135, Folder 1342)
    Gobelin Tapestries, buying and trying to sell same. On exhibition at the Metropolitan Museum of Art.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Duveen Brothers - Rugs, 1922-1933 (Box 135, Folder 1343)
    Purchase of Polonaise rugs, Ispahan Rug, Persian Hunting Rug, Corsini Rugs, etc. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. trying to bargain and exchange rugs with Duveen.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Duveen Brothers - Soviet, 1931 (Box 135, Folder 1344)
    Sir Joseph offers Russian pictures, John D. Rockefeller, Jr. refusal to have anything to do with them.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Furnishings - July Statement, 1914 (Box 135, Folder 1345)
    Lists of furnishings in house. Duplicates destroyed.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Furnishings, 1912-1931 (Box 135, Folder 1346)
  - 10 West 54th Street - P. W. French and Company, 1930-1939 (Box 135, Folder 1347)
    Offers of ancient tables and tapestries.
  - 10 West 54th Street - P. W. French and Company - Invoices, 1922-1934 (Box 135, Folder 1348)
  - 10 West 54th Street - Furnishings - Purchases, 1908-1951 (Box 135, Folder 1349)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. made various small purchases. Furniture repairing.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Gothic Tapestries from Larcade, 1922-1933 (Box 136, Folder 1350)
    "The Hunt of the Unicorn" purchased by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. in 1922. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. paid $1,100,000 for it. Discussion of a commission to George Gray Barnard. Importation difficulties. Descriptions of tapestry.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Gothic Tapestries from Larcade - United States Treasury Department, 1923 (Box 136, Folder 1351)
    Discussion of importation.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Gothic Tapestries from Larcade - Equitable Trust Company and Bankers Trust Company, 1923 (Box 136, Folder 1352)
    Handling payments, safekeeping of tapestries.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Gothic Tapestries from Larcade - Newspaper Articles, 1923 (Box 136, Folder 1353)
    Commenting on foreign sale, value of tapestries.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Theodore Hobby, 1914-1939 (Box 136, Folder 1354)
    Metropolitan Museum Far East Art Director. Gave John D. Rockefeller, Jr. professional opinions on various kinds of art. Made inventory of John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s porcelains. Helped John D. Rockefeller, Jr. build his porcelain collection. Helped in the photographing of the porcelains.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Theodore Hobby - Gifts and Compensation, 1915-1945 (Box 136, Folder 1355)
    Hobby received $22,500.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Martin Hofer, 1919-1923 (Box 136, Folder 1356)
    Porcelains and rugs offered for sale; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. declined offers.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Herter Looms, 1913-1922 (Box 136, Folder 1357)
    Repaired rugs, made slip covers for home, tapestries, lampshades. Redecorated dining room.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Nahmy A. Homsey, 1914-1915 (Box 136, Folder 1358)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. purchased several objects d'art in antique gold and bronze, total cost of purchases under $1000.00.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Heinrich Hofmann, 1929-1959 (Box 136, Folder 1359)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. purchase of three Hofmann paintings; donates them to the Riverside Church.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Kelekian, 1913-1959 (Box 136, Folder 1360)
    Sold Abby Aldrich Rockefeller some Persian miniatures and Chinese paintings. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. bought the Assyrian reliefs given to the University of Chicago from him. Purchase of rugs.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Frederick Keppel and Company, Inc., 1913-1932 (Box 136, Folder 1361)
    Lists of coaching prints and miscellaneous prints purchased by John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - 10 West 54th Street - M. Knoedler and Company, 1913-1938 (Box 136, Folder 1362)
    Purchase of prints which add to John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s coaching set. Information on cost and dates of purchase. Care and maintenance of pictures, frames, etc.
  - 10 West 54th Street - M. Knoedler and Company - Washington Portraits, 1920-1932 (Box 136, Folder 1363)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. buys Stuart's Washington for $40,000. Others declined.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Kouchakji Freres, 1914-1919 (Box 137, Folder 1364)
    Repair work on Rakka vases at home. Offer of Antioch chalice declined.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Kouchakji Freres - Greek Head "Maenad", 1916-1936 (Box 137, Folder 1365)
    Purchased in 1920 for $35,000 as 4th Century B.C. work. Authenticity questioned. Sold in 1936.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Kouchakji Freres, 1920-1959 (Box 137, Folder 1366)
  - 10 West 54th Street - M. Edouard Larcade, 1924-1927 (Box 137, Folder 1367)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. purchased furniture, rugs, porcelains and several objects d'art.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Library, 1927-1952 (Box 137, Folder 1368)
    Purchase of books. Printing of catalogue, 1936.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Library, 1927-1952 (Box 137, Folder 1369)
  - 10 West 54th Street - C. T. Loo, 1916-1949 (Box 137, Folder 1370)
  - 10 West 54th Street - Miscellaneous, 1916-1986 (Box 138, Folder 1371)
    Visitors to home. Interior decorators - L. Avavoine and Company. Small additions.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Miscellaneous - Purchase from Union College and Auburn Seminary, 1931 (Box 138, Folder 1372)
    Assyrian bas reliefs.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Miscellaneous - Samuel Gottscho Photographs, 1936-1969 (Box 138, Folder 1373)
    Interiors of 10 and 12 West 54th.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Paul Manship, 1914-1916 (Box 138, Folder 1374)
    Made flower boxes of terra cotta for house.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Metropolitan Museum of Art - Interest in Rockefeller Collection, 1936-1954 (Box 138, Folder 1375)
    Lists compiled by Theodore Hobby and Museum's curators on objects in John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s house which they would be interested in acquiring for the Museum.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Rufus E. Moore and Roland Moore, 1914-1949 (Box 138, Folder 1376)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. purchased some Chinese porcelains.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Paul Oechsle, 1913-1940 (Box 138, Folder 1377)
    Electrician and mechanic in home, general handy man.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Paintings Offered, 1921-1936 (Box 138, Folder 1378)
    All refused for various reasons. No real Rockefeller interest in these pictures.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Paintings Offered - Rose Cardwell Hughes, 1930-1935 (Box 138, Folder 1379)
    Tried to sell John D. Rockefeller, Jr. "Lansdonne" portrait of George Washington.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Paintings Offered - Franklin Portraits, 1925-1926 (Box 138, Folder 1380)
    Painted by DuPlessis, considered but not purchased.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Paintings Offered - Van der Weyden Portrait, 1926-1934 (Box 138, Folder 1381)
    Loan of portrait by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. to London showing.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Paintings Offered - Ainslie Galleries, 1927-1940 (Box 138, Folder 1382)
    One picture purchased, many declined.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Paintings Purchased - Lavoisier Portrait, 1925-1927 (Box 138, Folder 1383)
    Purchased from Wildenstein and Company. Given to Rockefeller Institute in 1927.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Paintings Offered - West Portrait of Franklin, 1926-1937 (Box 138, Folder 1384)
    Discussion of Benjamin West's authorship. Experts disagreed, still do.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Paintings Purchased, 1916-1931 (Box 138, Folder 1385)
    Van Gogh; Chinese painting "Hung Hsien." Excise tax on paintings.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Paintings Purchased - Lincoln Portraits - Ehrich Galleries, 1927-1934 (Box 138, Folder 1386)
    Offers of portraits of Lincoln, declined.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Paintings Purchased - Lincoln Portraits - Guy Stonestreet Purchase, 1928-1941 (Box 138, Folder 1387)
    Cogswell portrait purchased $20,000. Sent to Brown University in 1941.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Parish-Watson and Company, Inc., 1914-1927 (Box 139, Folder 1388)
    Purchase of porcelain and furniture. Negotiations over price.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Parish-Watson and Company, Inc., 1928-1943 (Box 139, Folder 1389)
  - 10 West 54th Street - Frank Partridge, 1924-1949 (Box 139, Folder 1390)
    Purchase of porcelain and furniture, candlesticks. Negotiations over price.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Frank Partridge, 1914-1923 (Box 139, Folder 1391)
  - 10 West 54th Street - Frank Partridge, 1914-1933 (Box 139, Folder 1392)
  - 10 West 54th Street - Paintings - Restoration, 1933 (Box 139, Folder 1393)
    Search for expert to work on pictures. No results in this file.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Memos of Purchases, 1926-1930 (Box 139, Folder 1394)
  - 10 West 54th Street - Porcelains, 1915-1941 (Box 140, Folder 1395)
    Offers of porcelains, comments on collection. Lending of pieces. Photographing, numbering porcelains. Visitors to see collection.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Porcelains - Lists, 1922-1960 (Box 140, Folder 1396)
    Master lists, Theodore Hobby's list, etc.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Porcelains - Loaned to Williamsburg, 1935-1937 (Box 140, Folder 1397)
    On loan, in Governor's Palace. Given in 1937.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Porcelains - Purchase from John D. Rockefeller, Sr., 1922 (Box 140, Folder 1398)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. buys porcelains from John D. Rockefeller. $780,000.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Porcelains - Miscellaneous Purchases, 1920-1955 (Box 140, Folder 1399)
    Small purchases from dealers and others. Mathias Komor. Dr. J. Hirsh. Mr. H. Bialia. Alice Boney. Evelyn B. Longman. Jacques Seligmann and Company. Parke-Bernet Galleries. Ralph M. Chait. St. James Gallery.
  - 10 West 54th Street - John D. Rockefeller, 1911-1925 (Box 140, Folder 1400)
    Transfer of property from John D. Rockefeller to John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Porcelains - Color Plate Engraving Company - Orders and Payments, 1919-1933 (Box 140, Folder 1401)
  - 10 West 54th Street - Porcelains - Color Plate Engraving Company, 1919-1958 (Box 140, Folder 1402)
    The making of color pictures of John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s porcelain collection. His concern with detail. Delays in work. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s dissatisfaction with some of the pictures. Reworking by Color Plate Engraving Company. Insistence on exact color conformity of photos with objects. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. purchased 25 copies of each plate.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Purchase from Mrs. John J. McCook, 1911 (Box 140, Folder 1403)
    Offered to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. at $225,000. He purchased the property at $200,000. Negotiations, details of deed.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Rugs, 1928-1929 (Box 141, Folder 1404)
    Purchase of Polonaise for $41,000 from Cleveland Museum of Art. Purchase of square Persian rug from Altman's for $30,000.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Rugs - Kent-Costikyan, 1920-1927 (Box 141, Folder 1405)
    Purchase of rugs. Negotiations.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Rugs - Loewi Rug, 1930 (Box 141, Folder 1406)
    Bought in Italy, $67,500. Persian animal.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Rugs - Polonaise Rug from Larcade, 1927-1929 (Box 141, Folder 1407)
    $110,000.00.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Rugs - Vitali Madjar, 1929 (Box 141, Folder 1408)
    Cairo, Egypt. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. paid $73,000 for rugs.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Rugs - Miscellaneous, 1914-1926 (Box 141, Folder 1409)
    Visitors. Offers of rugs, most declined. Small additions. Rug repairing.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Rugs - Lists, 1931 (Box 141, Folder 1410)
    Rugs owned by John D. Rockefeller, Jr., pictures, descriptions, histories of rugs and locations in house.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Rugs - Duty on Antique Rugs, 1925-1930 (Box 141, Folder 1411)
    Arthur U. Pope begins campaign to lower tariff on antique rugs. Report to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. on progress. No success as friends in Congress refuse to open tariff question there. Dragged on for several years. B. J. Sloan opposed revision violently. Finally passed in 1930 allowing rugs made before 1700 into country duty free.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Rugs - Polonaise Rugs, 1922-1943 (Box 141, Folder 1412)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. interested in acquiring such rugs and made inquiries. Started run on Polonaise rugs. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. bought three rugs from Duveen for $129,000. Bought two more from Duveen in 1923 for $82,000. Bought two more from Parish-Watson in 1927. Bought more in 1928.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Rugs - Arthur U. Pope - Sarre Rug, 1926-1932 (Box 142, Folder 1413)
    Arthur U. Pope bought Sarre rug in Paris. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. agreed to buy it from him in America at a fixed price later on. Rug repaired in Paris at John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s expense. It was a Persian animal carpet. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. guaranteed $40,000 loan so that Pope could buy the rug. Delivered to New York in 1927. Discussion of Pope's commission. Pope was an advisor to Philadelphia Museum.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Rugs - Arthur U. Pope - Ispenian Carpet, 1929 (Box 142, Folder 1414)
    Bought in New York through loan arrangement. Persian animal.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Rugs - Arthur U. Pope - Loan to Philadelphia Exhibition, 1926-1927 (Box 142, Folder 1415)
    Loan of rugs and tapestries by John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Rugs - Arthur U. Pope - General, 1926-1931 (Box 142, Folder 1416)
    Items bought to John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s attention by Arthur U. Pope. Question of Pope's integrity.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Sale of Art Objects and Furnishings, 1936 (Box 142, Folder 1417)
    Consignment of glass panels, porcelain stands, teak.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Sale of Art Objects and Furnishings - Parish-Watson, 1936-1937 (Box 142, Folder 1418)
    Took porcelains on consignment.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Sale of Art Objects and Furnishings - Kouchakji Freres, 1936-1937 (Box 142, Folder 1419)
    Handled two Rakka vases, could not sell them.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Sale of Art Objects and Furnishings - Brummer and Company, 1936 (Box 142, Folder 1420)
    Articles on consignment, no sales. Greek Bronze head, $1000.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Sale of Art Objects and Furnishings - Duveen Brothers, 1935-1937 (Box 142, Folder 1421)
    Tried to sell Laura Spelman Rockefeller portrait. Failed.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Sale of Art Objects and Furnishings - French and Company, 1944-1953 (Box 142, Folder 1422)
    Sale of old and modern stained glass.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Seligmann, Rey and Company, Inc., 1927-1928 (Box 142, Folder 1423)
    Italian table, $2500.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Servants, 1913-1938 (Box 142, Folder 1424)
    Accidents, insurance, trips, salaries.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Servants - Louis Herpe, 1917-1938 (Box 142, Folder 1425)
    Butler, had account with John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Silver, 1923-1930 (Box 142, Folder 1426)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. purchases from various dealers and galleries; some photographs.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Harry Skevington, 1927-1939 (Box 142, Folder 1427)
    Assistant engineer at 10 West 54th Street. Pay. Gifts.
  - 10 West 54th Street - John Sparks, 1920-1921 (Box 142, Folder 1428)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. purchased pair of Chinese famille-verte vases, a famille-verte jar and cover, yellow Kang'Hi square shape vase.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Steinway and Sons, 1938-1939 (Box 142, Folder 1429)
    Repair of pianos at 10 West 54th Street and Kykuit.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Arnold Talbot, 1914-1915 (Box 143, Folder 1430)
    Rhode Island weaver, friend of the Aldrich family, became friend of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Sold linens and towels to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. for homes.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Warwick House, Ltd., 1919-1920 (Box 143, Folder 1431)
    Purchasing Chinese porcelains, dishes, and vases. Confusion over payment of luxury tax.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Arthur S. Vernay, 1927-1932 (Box 143, Folder 1432)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. purchased porcelains, furniture, and silver.
  - 10 West 54th Street - L. Wannieck, 1927-1931 (Box 143, Folder 1433)
    Famille-verte beaker - Kang'Hi Period - $7000.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Tapestries, 1926-1938 (Box 143, Folder 1434)
    Offers of tapestries for home and Park Avenue Church investigated. Small additions.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Watchmen, 1917-1940 (Box 143, Folder 1435)
    Pay, hours, check-ups. Gifts. Troubles. Hiring and firing. Watchmen transferred to Cloisters when house demolished.
  - 10 West 54th Street - C. Edward Wells, 1929-1935 (Box 143, Folder 1436)
    Purchase of Assyrian reliefs. Negotiations on Egyptian heads fail.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Joseph E. Widner, 1917-1918 (Box 143, Folder 1437)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. purchased seated Chinese porcelain god, mate of one he already owned. Part of payment to Widner went to Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA) war effort and Playground and Recreation Association of America.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Wildenstein and Company, 1923-1931 (Box 143, Folder 1438)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. purchased paintings: "Portrait of a Lady" by Van der Weyden for $162,500; "Adeline Colombe" by Fragonard for $70,000; "Lavoisier and His Wife" by David for $150,000; a Nattier portrait for $150,000.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Wildenstein and Company - Invoices, 1925-1931 (Box 143, Folder 1439)
  - 10 West 54th Street - Edgar Worch, 1914-1950 (Box 144, Folder 1440)
    Purchase of Chinese porcelains and paintings.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Works of Art, 1924-1934 (Box 144, Folder 1441)
    Objects offered to John D. Rockefeller, Jr., all refused. Miscellaneous offers of pictures, busts, china, silver, etc.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Works of Art - Mrs. Rose C. Hughes, 1929-1930 (Box 144, Folder 1442)
    Tried to sell John D. Rockefeller, Jr. a Cellini shield.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Works of Art - P. Jackson Higgs, 1923-1946 (Box 144, Folder 1443)
    Offers of objects, all declined.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Works of Art - Loan for London Exhibition, 1931 (Box 144, Folder 1444)
    Request to use David painting in London, declined.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Works of Art - Purchases, 1911-1934 (Box 144, Folder 1445)
    Miscellaneous small purchases made by John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - 10 West 54th Street - Yamanaka and Company, 1909-1940 (Box 144, Folder 1446)
    Japanese house, purchase of cases, bronzes, etc.
- 4 West 54th Street, NYC
  - 4 West 54th Street, 1910-1921 (Box 145, Folder 1447)
    Relocation of wall at St. Thomas line. Portraits of John D. Rockefeller. Upkeep of house. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - 4 West 54th Street, 1924-1938 (Box 145, Folder 1449)
    1894 inventory of furniture purchased by John D. Rockefeller from C .P. Huntington. Repair work on home. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. distributes furniture from 4 West 54th Street to family after purchasing it from his father. Keebler urges immediate (1936) demolition to cut taxes. House demolished, 1937, to provide Abby Aldrich Rockefeller with bricks for home at Pocantico. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Robert W. Gumbel.
  - 4 West 54th Street - Use of Rooms for Red Cross Work, 1917-1926 (Box 145, Folder 1450)
  - 4 West 54th Street - Demolition, 1938 (Box 145, Folder 1451)
  - 4 West 54th Street - Closing #4, 1884 (Box 145, Folder 1452)
  - 4 West 54th Street - Gift of Rooms to Museum of the City of New York, 1935-1953 (Box 145, Folder 1453)
    Furniture and decoration from bedrooms. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - 4 West 54th Street - Household Inventory, March 24, 1913 (Box 146, Folder 1454)
    Inventory of contents of John D. Rockefeller's homes.
  - 4 West 54th Street - Household Inventory, March 24, 1913 (Box 146, Folder 1455)
  - 4 West 54th Street - Miscellaneous, 1918-1931 (Box 146, Folder 1456)
- 12 West 54th Street, NYC
  - 12 West 54th Street - Purchase, 1913-1919 (Box 145, Folder 1448)
    Purchased in 1917 for $125,000. Leased back to owner (prior) for two years. Correspondents include F. W. White, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
- One Beekman Place, NYC
  - One Beekman Place, 1956-1961 (Box 147, Folder 1457)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. held $1,000,000 mortgage on apartment building when it was built. Cooperative apartment was David Milton's project. Management, tenants. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., David Milton, Thomas M. Debevoise.
  - One Beekman Place - John D. Rockefeller 3rd - Employees, 1934-1961 (Box 147, Folder 1458)
    Christmas fund; wages; bonuses; aid to sick employees; 1956 Retirement Plan Study; insurance. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
    See front of box for two bound reports: Retirement Plan Study for One Beekman Place, Inc., June 1956, prepared by The Equitable Life Assurance Society of the U.S.; A Proposed Retirement Plan for One Beekman Place, n.d., presented by New York Life Insurance Company.
  - One Beekman Place - John D. Rockefeller 3rd - Employees - Employee Benefits, 1956-1959 (Box 147, Folder 1459)
    Insurance and pensions.
  - One Beekman Place - Underwriting and Mortgage, 1934-1957 (Box 147, Folder 1460)
    Details of John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s transaction with David Milton and One Beekman Place, Inc. Supplemental agreement of 1934. Corporation's payments on mortgage. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s assignment of mortgage to Prudential Insurance. Loans by John D. Rockefeller 3rd and Abby Rockefeller Milton/Pardee/Mauze to corporation. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Charles O. Heydt, Phillip Keebler, David Milton.
  - One Beekman Place - Underwriting and Mortgage, 1929-1934 (Box 147, Folder 1461)
  - One Beekman Place, 1934-1944 (Box 148, Folder 1462)
  - One Beekman Place, 1944-1952 (Box 148, Folder 1463)
  - One Beekman Place - John D. Rockefeller 3rd - Alterations to Apartment, 1932-1936 (Box 148, Folder 1464)